# Yu-Wen Pu 蒲郁文

Email: <a href="mailto:ywpu@cs.nctu.edu.tw">ywpu@cs.nctu.edu.tw</a> Linkedin: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/ywpu">https://linkedin.com/in/ywpu</a> Website: <a href="https://ywpu.me">https://ywpu.me</a>

## **SUMMARY**

I enjoy interdisciplinary learning and have taken courses in computer science and social sciences. I have some experience in software development and user experience design. I am interested in designing digital services for communities and studying the relation between digital technology and civil society using empirical methods.

#### **SKILLS**

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6+),
   Vue, PHP, Python, R, SQL, Git, Linux, GCP
- User-centered product design process
- Conducting user interviews, designing experiments and usability tests, planning workshops and facilitating discussions
- Data (text) analysis and visualization
- Information society studies (using empirical methods)

### **EXPERIENCE**

Front-end Engineer, AJA Creative Design (Taiwan-based UX design agency) — June 2021 – Present

Managing an internal product, from planning and designing, to developing and launch; creating maximal value under limited resources

- Coordinates with executives to determine the scope, schedule, and resource of the project; conducts user interviews to identify their pain points and expectations; collaborates with designers to find out solutions together
- Develops the front-end and the back-end
- Collects user feedback continually and iterates the product every 1–2 weeks
- The new product successfully improves colleagues' workflow, and colleagues say it has better user experience compared with the old one

Other Responsibilities:

 Collaborates with designers to create excellent user experience; discusses technical feasibility and complexity with designers; builds front-end web applications  Organizes and runs design workshops with designers and researchers; conducts stakeholder interviews with designers and project managers

Research Assistant, National Center for Highperformance Computing, National Applied Research Labs — Mar. 2019 – July 2019 Summer Intern, National Center for Highperformance Computing, National Applied Research Labs — July 2018 – Aug. 2018

Project: Using Big Data to Analyze Gender Differences in Attitudes Toward Air Pollution Issues

- Studied and practiced text mining methods with R and tidyverse; helped refine a text mining book while studying
- Performed data collection, data cleaning, word segmentation, keyword extraction, topic extraction (document clustering), and sentiment analysis with Python, SciPy, R, and tidyverse

Summer Student – IT Staff, Tainan Manufacturing Center, Applied Materials Taiwan – July 2017 – Aug. 2017

Project: Designing and Developing a Web Client for a Production Monitoring System

- Worked with manufacturing engineers and managers to build a web app that can visualize real-time fab status, query data, post announcements, and control access according to user's privilege level
- Developed the front-end and the back-end

Summer Intern, Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica — July 2016 – Aug. 2016

Project: Designing and Developing a Biodiversity Analysis Application

- Collaborated with teammates to build a GUI app that can import species occurrence datasets, visualize the spatial/temporal distribution of species, calculate the spatial/temporal relation between species, and find out the co-occurrences of species
- Developed with Python, SciPy, Qt (via PyQt)

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science (M.S.) in Computer Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University — Sept. 2018 – Feb. 2021

GPA: 4.11

Master's Thesis: Designing an Interactive Interface That Facilitates Public Deliberation Based on Social Relations

- Conducted interviews to identify design directions of public deliberation technologies
- Developed an interactive prototype using frontend and back-end technologies
- Conducted an online discussion experiment to evaluate the efficacy and user experience of the proposed design (similar to an A/B test)

Project: Designing Culture Weaver, a Mobile Application for Preserving and Curating Local Culture and History, Through User-Centered Design Processes

 Worked with teammates to define a design problem, conduct stakeholder interviews, identify design requirements, create personas and scenarios, create wireframes, create mockups and prototypes with Figma, and conduct usability tests for design iterations

Project: Researching the User Experience of Gongqibubei, a Mobile Application for Learning English

 Worked with teammates and Hopenglish (the company behind Gongqibubei) to create an interaction map of the product; conduct user interviews, comparative (competitive) analysis, a survey, heuristic evaluations, and usability tests for the product

Program of Cultural Studies, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University — Sept. 2018 – Feb. 2021 Took several courses in sociology, philosophy, and communication studies

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science, National Chiao Tung University — Sept. 2014 – June 2018

GPA: 3.93 (Class Rank: 5 out of 50)

Bachelor's Thesis: Analysis of Political Activities on Social Networking Sites

 Performed data collection, pre-processing, word segmentation, keyword/event extraction, document classification (positive or negative campaigning), and social network analysis with Python, Gephi, and PHP

## **AWARDS**

Undergraduate Research Competition,
Honorable Mention — Awarded by Department
of Computer Science, National Chiao Tung
University, Dec. 2017

My research project "Analysis of Political Activities on Social Networking Sites" received an honorable mention

Academic Achievement Award — Awarded by National Chiao Tung University, Apr. 2015

I ranked first in a class of 48 in the Fall 2014 semester

Application Design Contest, 2nd Place — Awarded by Information Technology Services Center, National Chiao Tung University, Sept. 2015 (with a team of 4)

Application Design Contest, 3rd Place — Awarded by Information Technology Services Center, National Chiao Tung University, Sept. 2014 (with a team of 4)

A full-stack web development contest that required teams to design and implement a web application according to a given specification within a limited time